（确定删除文件吗）
（文件删除中）
（Oscorp工业基因实验室）
（访问被拒绝 用户ID失效 文件暂停访问）
人们因为我的所作所为而称我为怪物
People will say I'm a monster for what I've done.
也许他们是对的
Maybe they're right.
我总以为我还有很多时间
I always thought that I'd have more time.
爸爸
Dad.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
彼得
Peter?
- 他睡觉的时候喜欢开着灯 - 玛丽 我们得走了
- He likes to sleep with the lights on. - Mary, we have to go.
爸爸
Dad.
要听话
Be good.
我找到了一个安全的地方过夜 在日内瓦湖
I have found a safe place for us to spend the night, at Lake Geneva.
- 你在上传吗 - 传到「罗斯福」上 全都传了
- Are you uploading it? - To Roosevelt. All of it.
万一我们
Just in case we…
会没事的 玛丽
It'll be fine, Mary.
你看到他的表情了吗 他永远也不会理解
Did you see his face? He ​​is never gonna understand.
玛丽 这事我们已经讨论过了 我们没法回到原本的生活了
Mary we've been through this. Our life as we know it is over.
从今天起我们每天都要提心吊胆地生活
We will spend every day from now on looking over our shoulders…
永远不会感到安全 我们不能让他也这样
Never feeling safe. We can't do that to him.
- 他只是个小男孩 - 我知道 会没事的
- He's just a little boy. - I know. It's going to be ok.
会没事的
It's gonna be alright.
- 一刻都无法停歇啊 - 恐怕是的
- No rest for the weary hah. - No, I'm afraid not.
所谓的职业危害吧
Occupational hazard I guess.
你在忙些什么
What is it you're working on?
提前做些计划 你觉得我能跟机长谈谈吗
Just planning ahead. Do you think I could speak to the pilot?
你需要什么 也许我能帮上忙
Something you need? Perhaps I can help.
我想提前联系一下地面人员
I'd just like to radio ahead,
确保我们到达后一切都安排好了
and make sure everything's in order for when we land.
我们都知道这是不可能的 帕克博士
I think We both know that's not an option, Dr. Parker.
理查德
Richard!
- 他们说你是个天才 - 理查德
- They say you're a genius. - Richard!
你要是认为你能逃掉的话就不是了
Not if you thought you could escape.
玛丽
Mary!
没事了
It's okay.
有我呢 你怎么样
I got you. Okay?
我会让你没事的 好了 呼吸 玛丽
I'm going to make you safe. It's done.It's Done.Breathe.Mary.
- 「罗斯福」 - 什么 - 「罗斯福」
- Roosevelt. - What? - Roosevelt.
重连上了 重连上了
It's back on. It's back on. Okay?
听着 我们会没事的 听我说
Hey, hey hey. We'll be alright. Okay? Listen to me.
今天又会发生什么事呢 纽约
What you got for me today, New York?
纽约一号频道现场播报
Reporting live from the New York One chopper.
Oscorp工业一辆载有钚的卡车被劫持
An Oscorp truck carrying plutonium has been hijacked.
警方已经开始追踪
A Police chase is in progress.
好的 我们开工吧
Alright let's get to work.
跟阿列克谢·西斯艾维奇打个招呼吧
Say hello to Aleksei Sytsevich.
- 蜘蛛侠 - 你们好啊
- Spider-Man. - Hello, pedestrians.
开门呀
Knock. Knock.
罪犯先生
Mr. Criminal.
嘿 我的名字叫蜘蛛侠
Hey. My name is SpiderMan,
你可以叫我网格头 也可以叫我超凡小虫
You can call me web head, you can call me amazing.
但就是别大半夜叫我吃饭 懂了吗
Just don't call me late for dinner. You get it?
不喜欢握手 难道喜欢拥抱吗
Not a handshake? Are you a hugger?
- 我可是杀人犯！- 好吧 随你便咯
- I'm a killer. - Who! Okay!
警告 钚-238是放射性物质
WARNING. Plutonium-238 is a radioactive material.
并且易爆
and is highly explosive.
借过一下 别挤着我好吗
Excuse me. There's room for all of us on the sidewalk.
我抱着图纸呢 帮个忙好吗 有人帮个忙吗
Please I've got blueprints here. A little help, a little help, please.
你的枪出了什么问题吗
You're having problems with your gun?
让我帮帮你吧
Let me help you out with that.
小心 有车辆通过
Oh, coming through.
这可是我的作品
It's my work.
不好 我马上回来
This is bad. I'm gonna be right back.
小心
Watch out.
好的 没事了 你怎么样
Okay. There you go. Are you okay?
- 你还好吧 - 你是蜘蛛侠
- You alright. - You're Spider-Man.
从衣服上看出来的哈 这些很重要 迈克斯
Costume gives the way hah? Look, these looks pretty important, Max.
- 你怎么知道我的名字 - 你的胸章上面写的
- How do you know my name? - Its written on your badge.
- 我只是个无名小卒 - 嘿 你不是 你是个重要人物
- I'm a nobody. - Hey! You're not a nobody, you're a somebody.
舔一下 听我说
Lick that. Listen to me.
而且我需要你 你就是我在这儿的眼睛和耳朵
And I need you. You're my eyes and ears out here.
- 好吗 - 好的 - 回头见
- Alright! - Alright. - See you out there.
警告 违规操作
Warning: Violation of protocol.
举起手来
Hands up.
抓住了 抓住了 还有你
Gotcha, gotcha. No. I got you, too.
嘿 还有你 你哪也跑不了 过来 上爸爸这儿来
Hey you you.No, you're not going anywhere. Come here, come to daddy.
都闪开
Get out of the way.
停下 停下
Stop it. Stop it.
噢 别闹
Oh come on.
嘿 等下 快回来
Hey wait. Come back here.
抓住你了
Gotcha.
嘿 抱歉 我要迟到一会儿
Hey, I'm sorry. I'm running a bit late.
我堵车了
I got stuck in some traffic.
你还真会挑时间 已经开始了
Your timing is terrible. It's started already.
- 我知道 对不起 - 你到哪儿了
- I know. I'm sorry. - Where are you?
百老汇大街 一街 二街 三街了
First in Broadway. Second in Broadway. Third in Broadway.
五分钟就到 最多十分钟
Five minutes, ten tops.
我听到的是警笛吗
Are those sirens?
不是
No.
- 彼得 - 不是
- Peter - No!
- 彼得 - 不是警笛呀
- Peter. - No sirens.
彼得 发生了什么
Peter, what is happening.
彼得
Peter.
喂
Hello.
- 我来向大家介绍位非常优秀的女士 - 我保证马上就到了
- Now I'd like to introduce an extraordinary young lady. - I'll be right there. Promise.
有请今年的毕业生代表 格温·斯黛西
This year's valedictorian. Please welcome, Gwen Stacy.
早上好 尊敬的各位教职员工 毕业生及其家人们
Good morning, esteemed faculty and families of my fellow graduates.
非常荣幸站在这里
It's an honor to be standing up here today.
嘿 我跟你说啊 我赶时间呢
Hello… I told you, I am running a bit late.
- 你完蛋啦小蜘蛛 哈哈哈哈 - 是么？
- I saw the Spider. Hahahaha. - Really?
我们都认为自己拥有无限光阴
I know that we all think we're immortal.
很理所当然的想法 虽然我们毕业了
We're supposed to feel that way, We're graduating.
但就像这短暂的高中生活
But like our brief four years in high school.
生命的可贵便在于她无法永垂不朽
What makes life valuable is that it doesn't last forever.
因为有限 所以珍贵
What makes it precious is that it ends.
现在的我们最深有体会
We know that now more than ever.
我之所以
And I say it…
在今天说这些
today of all days.
是为了提醒我们 时光易逝
to remind us that time is luck.
不要把它浪费在无关紧要的事上
So don't waste it living someone else's life.
着眼自身 让你的人生变得有意义
Make yours count for something.
无论如何 为你心中的最重要的事而奋斗
Fight for what matters to you, no matter what.
这样即使我们无法永生
And even if we fall short,
我们也没有辜负这段光阴
what better way is there to live?
我拿走啦 这不属于你
I'll take that. That's not yours.
我们之间还没完 小蜘蛛
This is not ends, Spider.
彼得·帕克
Peter Parker.
我觉得我认识那个人
I think I know that guy.
彼得·帕克
Peter Parker.
对不起
Sorry.
等下 再来一次 再来一次
Wait, do that again, do that again.
我差点就要去偷长袍和帽子替你上台了
I almost stole a cap and gown and run up there myself.
我好想看看那场面 别照了
I'd love to have seen that.That would have been pretty awesome. No, no, no.
看 这是给你的
Look, this is for you.
我真为你感到骄傲 孩子 我真为你感到自豪
I am so proud of you. Sweetheart, I'm so proud of you.
- 我知道你本叔叔最先会说什么 - 我也知道
- I know the first thing Uncle Ben would say. - I know, too.
「你得抓紧了 派对已经结束了
"You got to hurry up the party's over.
- 不是 - 你要步入社会找份工作了「
- No. - You gotta go out and get a job."
好吧 但他接下来会说
Alright, the second thing he would say:
「不要随波逐流 要找到自己的路」
"Don't just follow the path. Make your own trail."
- 爱默生说的 - 不是
- Ralph Waldo Emerson. - No.
为什么说不是
What do you mean no?
本说是他原创的
Ben told me he'd made it up.
你真的在这里学到了东西
You really did learn something here.
我希望你叔叔能在这里
I wish your uncle could have been here.
是 我也是 还有我父母
Yeh me too. And my folks.
是啊是啊
Yeh, yeh.
好了 你可以走了 快去吧
Alright, you could go. Go on.
你们快来 一起照一张 快点
Guys, get together, get together right now.
- 快 格温 茄子 - 茄子
- Quick Gwen. Alright. Cheese. - Cheese.
给我两秒钟
Yeh.Just gimme two seconds.
- 别走太远 - 很高兴见到你
- Don't go too far away. - Good to see you.
嘿 你的堵车不会碰巧和这群俄罗斯人劫匪
Did your traffic jam have anything to do with the Russian mob.
还有这些机枪有关吧
And machine guns, by any chance?
为什么不告诉我
Why don't you just tell me?
你就要演讲了我怎么能跟你说这些
Because what am I gonna do? You were about to give a speech.
- 格温 亲爱的 家庭合照 - 好的
- Gwen. Honey, family photos. - Okay.
- 嘿 你来家庭聚餐吗 - 想不让我来都不行
- Hey, you coming to Dim Sum? - You can't keep me away.
- 晚上八点 别迟到了 - 现在就饿了
- It's at eight o'clock. Don't be late. - I'm hungry.
好的
OK.
我会再给你演讲一遍
And I'm gonna do my speech to you.
整晚 我愿意一整晚都听这个
All night. I want to hear it all night long.
一遍又一遍 整个晚上
Over and over again, all night long.
彼得 一起来吧 快来
Peter, join us? Come on.
我需要去找我伯母了
I gotta find my aunt, I gotta find my aunt.
但是我过会儿回来找你们 谢谢
But I'm gonna catch up later. Thank you.
你将会树敌 会有人受伤
You gonna make enemies. People will get hurt.
我需要你向我保证
So I want you to promise me something, ok?
不要把格温卷进来
Leave Gwen out of this.
答应我
Promise me that.
彼得在外面
Peter's outside.
彼得
Peter.
怎么了
What is it?
怎么了 你还好吗
What's wrong? Are you alright?
我不知道我在做什么
I don't know what I'm doing.
是我父亲 对吗
It's my father, right?
是 我走到哪都能看见他
Yes, I see him everywhere I go.
我不知道该怎么办 他在我脑中挥之不去
I don't know what to do. I can't get him out of my head.
- 但我们之前都讨论清楚了 - 我知道
- Yes, but we'd talked about this. - Yeah, I know…
这不是他能决定的
It's not his choice.
我答应他 我会和你保持距离
I promised him that I would keep away from you.
而我现在却要来和你的家人吃晚餐
And now I'm gonnna come and eat dinner with your family.
我怎么能这么做 我成什么了
How can I do this? What does this make me?
我不知道这样做让你成了什么
I don't know I don't know what does that make you.
这让我无法原谅我自己
It makes me not able to live with myself.
- 我以为这意味着你爱我 - 我是爱你
- I thought that it would make you love me? - I do love you.
我爱你
I love you.
那这还不够吗
Then why isn't that enough? Hmm.
如果你发生什么
Because what if something happens to you,
就像他一样 因为我的关系
just like it happened to him, because of me?
不 等等
No, wait wait wait.
我不能让这种事发生
I cannot let that happen.
听我说 你是蜘蛛侠
Listen to me, you are Spider-Man.
我爱蜘蛛侠
And I love that.
但我更爱彼得·帕克
But I love Peter Parker more.
对我来说 这很值得
That's worth it to me.
我不能连你也失去
I cannot lose you too.
因为你不能失去我 所以我们不能在一起
Because you can't lose me, we can't be together?
这样做对谁有好处
Who does that work out for, Peter?
我做不到 我很抱歉 格温
I can't. I'm sorry, Gwen.
你一次又一次这样
You have done this to me…
对我 彼得
Again, again… Peter.
我承受不了了
I can't live like this.
我们分手吧
I break up with you.
是我要跟你分手
I broke up with you.
早上好 纽约
Good morning, New Yorkers.
又迎来了美好的一天
Looking for another beautiful day here in the city.
人们越来越多地在城市中见到蜘蛛侠
The city increases in sightings of Spider-Man,
引发了全国关于警察在美国打击犯罪中作用的讨论
Spark a national debate over the role of vigilantes in American crime fighting.
关于蜘蛛侠 他昨晚又在曼哈顿桥拯救了数十人的性命
How about that Spider-Man? Last night on Manhatten Bridge he saved a dozen lives.
欢迎致电与我们共同讨论
We want to hear your calls.
我觉得没有蜘蛛侠这座城市就没有了希望
I think without Spider-Man there is no hope for this city.
你以为是谁在为他造成的破坏买单
Who do you think pays the bill for all the damages he causes?
是你我这些纳税人
It's you and me the taxpayer.
- 这是你做的吗 - 是的
- Did you make this? - Yes.
这可是风力涡轮机 你做的 开什么玩笑
This is a wind turbine. You made this? No way!
简直巧夺天工
This is amazing.
跟没坏一样 对吧 我陪你走回家
It's good as new, right? I'll walk you home.
- 你叫什么名字 - 豪尔赫
- What's your name? - Jorge.
豪尔赫你好 我叫蜘蛛侠
Jorge, I'm Spider-Man.
他在外面晃荡 我担心孩子们的安全
I don't feel like my kids are safe with him out there,
少管闲事 让警察做他们的工作
get out of the way and let the police do their job.
有些人认为蜘蛛侠不止一个
Some folks think that there might be more than one Spider-man.
你们怎么看 他是独行侠还是一个团队
What do you think, one guy or many?
我真想见见面具后面那张脸
I'd love to know who's behind that mask.
- 扮得不错 - 多谢
- Hey, nice outfit. - Thanks.
有一位观众来电 他叫迈克斯
We have a caller on the line named Max,
声称他认识蜘蛛侠
he said he knows Spider-Man.
听着 我很伤心 蜘蛛侠被误会了
Listen, I'm upset…Spider-Man to me is being misunderstood.
他是个大好人 一直在保护我们
He's a very, very good person, He's protecting us.
不仅如此 他救过我的命
Not only that, he saved my life onetime.
然后我们就成了好兄弟
and we sort of became best friends.
- 多少钱 - 你是那个蜘蛛男
- How much? - You're that Spider guy!
我是蜘蛛虾
I'm Spider-Bad.
这个蜘蛛侠 他不是警察 也不是消防员
This Spider-Man guy, he's not the police, he's not a fireman.
那他是凭什么
What gives him the right,
管别人的闲事呢
to get involved in other people's business.
彼得 亲爱的 我能进来吗
Peter, honey, can I come in?
不行
No!
彼得 期末考试九点就开始了
Peter, the final starts at nine, honey.
而且你说过 车老是坏
And you said you'd take my car.
你要把它送到修理厂 记得吗
into the shop b'coz it keeps dying, remember?
再等会儿 梅伯母
Gimme a second, I'll be out.
我马上去开门 很快就好了
I'm gonna get the door, just gimme a second.
就让我进去 好吗
Please just let me in, alright?
我在努力把鞋给
I'm…trying to get…
- 九点期末考 你还有空把车送修吗 - 好的 马上来了
- The final is at 9, are you going to take my car to the shop? - YES. Just give me a…
你呆在外面别进来 我什么都没穿
No, you can't come in. Stay outside, I'm so naked.
彼得 老天爷啊
Peter, for goodness's sake.
你说你会把车送去修理的
You said you're gonna take my car into the shop because…
- 你没事吧 - 好着呢
- Are you alright? - Yeah. I'm okay.
我现在 就是什么都没穿
I'm just…I'm very naked right now.
你的脸怎么这么脏
What happened to your face, it's filthy!
- 脏吗 - 脏死了
- Is it? - Yes.
哦 我刚才清理完烟囱
Oh yeah, yeah, I was cleaning the chimney.
- 咱家没烟囱 - 什么
- We have no chimney. - What?
- 你要迟到了 - 我知道了
- You're late. - I know, I'm late.
- 下楼 - 我还不
- Downstairs… - I can't.
- 马上 - 你能先离开一下么
- Now! - Can you…can you leave.
- 好 我走 - 我什么都没穿
- Alright, I'm leaving! - I'm naked here.
- 早上好 我爱你 - 我也爱你 快起来
- Morning. I love you. - I love you too. Hurry up.
（迈克斯和蜘蛛侠携手拯救纽约城）
瞧瞧谁来了 小蜘蛛
Ho ho ho, look who's here? Spidey!
早上好吗 好极了 迈克斯
How was your morning? Aces, Max, aces.
我忙着拯救世界 保护市民
I've been out saving the world, protecting everybody.
猜猜今天谁过生日
Listen, isn't it somebody's birthday today?
你来就是为了这个 你记得我的生日
That's why you're here. You remembered my birthday.
虽然你忙着打击犯罪
All the crime fighting you've been doing.
但你还是抽空来看望卑微的我
and all of a sudden you take time to visit little old me, Max.
你真是 太好了
That's…it's amazing.
不过当然了 你怎么会不来看我呢
But…of course you would, why won't you visit me?
我们可是好兄弟
We're best friend.
你也太贴心了吧 给我烤了个蛋糕
What are you doing? You made me a cake?
真该让别人看看
People don't get the chance.
你对民众是多么贴心
to see these all kind things you do for people.
我知道媒体是怎么说你的
I know what they say about.
但是我不在乎
you in the press but it doesn't matter to me.
因为我认识真实的你 超凡的你
because I know the real you, because you're amazing.
对了 媒体就缺这个
Wow, that's what the press needs.
他们应该叫你超凡蜘蛛侠
They should call you "The Amazing Spider-Man."
你喜欢吗 小蜘蛛 我很喜欢 迈克斯
You like that, Spidey? I like it a lot, Max.
今天一定会是个超凡的日子
Good…because today is going to be amazing.
39号电路
Circuit thirty nine.
我没迟到 哈维 给我15分钟
I'm not late, Harvey, I'll be there in fifteen minutes.
我只想问问你能不能找个服务员代我
I just wanna know if you can find another waitress to replace me.
因为我在医院的培训开始了
because I start my training rounds at the hospital.
别告诉彼得
Don't mention this to Peter,
他要是知道肯定会担心
I don't want him to know because he worries, that's all.
好的好的 周四我做两份工 再见
Yeah, yeah, okay, you got it. Double shift on Thursday. Okay bye.
- 刚才那是谁 - 哈维
- Who was that? - Harvey.
- 又是两份工吗 - 偶尔
- Another double shift, huh? - Sometimes.
闲着也是闲着 同事们也都挺好的
I got nothing else to do, I like the girls,
我想本了 还能挣点零花钱
I missed Ben, gives me a little extra in the cookie jar.
我又卖了几张照片
I sold another, another.
卖给号角日报 也能帮上忙
couple of photos to the Bugle so that outa help.
你老板能付合理的薪酬才叫帮忙
Yeah, what really help if that guy would pay you a fair wage.
你说詹姆森吗 他会给我合理的薪酬
Oh, Jameson? Jameson would pay me some fair wages,
如果这是1961年 他会给我合理的薪酬
if it was 1961, he would pay me a fair wage.
嘿 你干什么呢 干什么呢
Hey, Hey, wait. What are you doing? What are you doing?
- 要洗衣服啊 - 不 衣服我来洗
- I'm doing my laundry. - No, I do the laundry.
这是我的活 从你6岁起
It's my job, I've been doing.
你的衣服就是我洗的
your laundry since you were six years old.
我知道 但我都要上大学了
I understand that, I'm in college now,
我的内裤也该我自己洗了
it's time that I took care of my own dirty underwear.
上次你自己洗的时候
The last time you did the laundry,
出来的全成了蓝色或者红色
you turned everything blue and red.
那是无心之过 因为
That was a mistake, cause' I was.
我在洗美国国旗 你就让
washing…the…the American flag, my…can you just please…
没人会去洗国旗的
No one washes the flag.
我会 以后不会了 这事别提了
I do and I won't anymore, forget it,
- 就让我自己 只是内裤而已 - 这是我的洗衣机
- fine, can I just do my…it's just underwear! - This is my machine.
这是我家 衣服我来洗
This is my laundry, my home,
洗衣机我来用 退后 吃你的早饭
my machine. Back off, eat your breakfast.
遵命 洗衣警长 我等会儿再洗
Alright laundry sheriff. I'll do it later.
- 我来洗 - 算了吧
- I'll do it. - No, forget it.
- 给我吧 - 我再找时间自己洗吧
- Give it to me. - No, I'll do it some other time, forget it.
- 不好意思 - 白痴
- Excuse me. - Idiot.
我就不懂了
I do not get it.
要堵死了 快点快点
A lot of jam. Come on, come on.
- 看着点 伙计 - 快走
- Watch it, buddy. - Hey, let's go!
Oscorp工业有幸宣布
Oscorp Industries is proud to announce…
已架设好世界上首个电磁输电网络
the world's first electromagnetic power grid.
通过将老旧的发电厂
by converting aging power stations.
改建为新的水力发电塔
into a field of hydro electric towers…
我们生产绿色可持续的洁净能源
we're generating clean, green, sustainable energy…
满足曼哈顿 乃至全世界的能源需求
to power Manhatten… and finally the rest of the world…
- 狄龙 你迟到了 - 双层列车太慢了 先生
- Dillon, you're late. - Double Decker trains were so slow, sir.
你难道不知道Oscorp现在
Don't you realise that Oscorp is.
负责整个城市的能源供应吗
now responsible for the entire city's energy supply?
当然了 我提交了很多关于电网的设计
Oh, I do. I submitted the designs for the power grid and they used a lot of them.
而我发现你们用的正是我的设计
and I noticed that in those power grids were designed by me.
你说你设计了电网 我还说我是蜘蛛侠呢
You designed them? Sure you did and I'm Spider-Man.
你才不是蜘蛛侠 他是狮子座而你是人马座
You're no Spider-Man. He's a Leo you're a Sagittarius!
你再敢提起他试试
You ever speak about him again,
看我不把你的脑袋拧下来
I'm gonna rip your flat-goon head off.
干活去
Now get to work.
- 请问您要去几层 - 74层
- Which floor please - 74.
谢谢
Thank you.
帮忙按一下电梯
Oh, hold that!
- 别担心 - 谢谢 你真是个绅士
- I got it. - Thank you, you're a real gentleman.
大部分人都直接让门关上了
Most people would just let that close.
大部分人不关心别人
Well, most people don't notice other people.
- 请问你要去几层 - 63层
- Which floor please - 63.
- 别急 几层来着 - 呃 63层
- Hold on. What's it? - Er…63.
- 63层 - 谢谢
- 63, please - Thank you.
十分感谢
Thank you, very much.
我叫迈克斯 迈克斯·狄龙
Er…my name is Max, Max Dillon.
- 我叫格温 很高兴认识你 - 很高兴认识你
- I'm Gwen. Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
今天是你生日吗
Is it your birthday?
呃 对 没错 我
Oh yeah, well, I…er,
他们 在我房间留了这个传单
they…fortunately leave this flyer in my room…
生日派对 大场子 名人都会来
birthday party, big club… A lot of celebrities…
- 哇 - 我本可以邀请你的
- Wow. - I would like to invite you,
但是宾客名单已经定下来了
it's just that the guest list is closed.
明白了 还是谢谢你 听起来很热闹
Oh, got it, got it but thank you anyway. This's exciting.
一定很有意思
It must be cool, huh,
全世界都这么关注你
to have the whole world look at you like that.
蜘蛛侠救了我一命
You know Spider-Man saved my life one time.
茫茫人海中他救了我
Of all the people in the whole city, he saved me.
他说他需要我
He said he needed me.
那一定很
That must be really…
63层到了
Floor 63.
很高兴认识你 迈克斯
It's nice to meet you, Max.
等等 她记得我的名字
Wait, she remembered my name.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
里面很暗
It's dark in there.
你的眼睛会适应的
Your eyes will adjust.
还是暗点好
It's better this way.
爸
Dad.
没想到我会这样死去
This is not how I imagined I'd die.
看着我的儿子 跟看陌生人一样
Looking at my son, seeing a stranger.
哈利 你前途无量
You had such potential, Harry.
你明明智商超群 却把它拒之门外
Such fierce intelligence and yet you're throwing it all away.
是你把我拒之门外
You threw me away.
我11岁你就把我送到了寄宿学校
You kicked me off to boarding school when I was eleven.
我16岁生日那天
On my 16th birthday…
你就送了一瓶威士忌 又或者是你助理送的
you sent me scotch, or one of your assistants did.
估计是后者 因为卡上写着
I'm pretty sure because the card read:
请笑纳 诺曼·奥斯本敬上
With compliments, Norman Osborn.
我不指望你的原谅 再也不会了
I don't expect forgiveness from you, any more.
你猜怎么着 我不相信奇迹
and you know what? I don't believe in miracles.
你又怎么会明白
How could you possibly understand…
你的童年必须被牺牲掉
that your childhood had to be sacrificed.
来换取更重要的东西
for something greater?
不只是为了我 还是为了你好
Not just for me, for you!
你的手开始抽搐了没
Have your hands started to twitch yet?
当你夜不能寐
When you lay awake…
感受到它的侵袭
and you feel it coming…
藏匿在皮肤之下
hiding under the skin…
随时准备显形
waiting to show itself…
暴露出你的本来面目
to show you who you really are…
逆转录细胞增生症
Retroviral Hyperplasia.
我从没告诉你
I never told you…
它是遗传病
that's genetic.
家族遗传
Our disease,
奥斯本家的诅咒
the Osborn curse.
就在你这个年龄开始发作
and it began at your age.
让我看看
Let me see it.
把手给我
Your hand, give it to me.
我留给你最重要的遗产
The greatest inheritance I can give you.
不只是财富
isn't merely money,
而是这个
is this…
我的毕生心血
A sum total of all my work,
我为续命所做的一切
everything I did to stay alive.
或许你能完成我未竟的事业
Maybe you can succeed where I failed.
尊敬的詹姆森 新的照片 发票已附
Dear Mr Jameson New pix and invoice enclosed.
您可以考虑一下
I think you should consider.
或许蜘蛛侠是想帮忙
that maybe Spider-man is trying to help.
敬上 彼得·帕克
Sincerely, Peter Parker.
新闻播报 诺曼·奥斯本先生 Osborn工业
News just in, Mr Norman Osborn, the legendary.
伟大的创建者和首席执行官刚刚去世
founder and CEO of Oscorp Industries has died.
奥斯本的遗产确认
The Osborn estate has confirmed.
被他的独子继承
he is survived by his only son,
哈利·奥斯本 他是
Harry Osborn, who is the sole heir.
Oscorp商业帝国的唯一继承人
of the Oscorp corporate empire.
奥斯本从根本上改变了
Osborn fundamentaly changed the.
医疗业治疗疾病的方式
medical profession's approach to human healing…
影响了数以百万计的生命
and affected the lives of millions.
我建立Oscorp是因为
I started Oscorp because I.
我看看我身边的世界 我想
looked at the world around me and I thought.
我们可以做得更好 我们应该做的更好
"We can do better. We should do better."
爱因斯坦说过
Einstein said the world.
只有改变思维方式 世界才会因此改变
cannot be changed without changing our thinking.
但改变不仅仅是一句口号
but change isn't just a slogan.
它始于勤恳
It begins with hard work.
改变是始于坚持和投入的
Change begins with persistence and commitment.
奥斯本先生改变了世界
Mr. Osborn changed the world.
而现在是时候让我们每个人
and now it's up to each of us.
来延续他的希望和梦想
to ensure that his hopes and dreams remain alive.
但不是从今天开始
but not today.
- 今天是 - 喂
- Today… - Hello?
- 请问是格温·斯黛西吗 - 我是 请问您是
- Is this Gwen Stacy? - Yes, it's, who's calling?
这里是牛津大学奖学金项目组
I'm calling from the Oxford scholar program.
告诉你一个好消息
We've some exciting news.
哦 狄龙 你得留下来
Oh, Dillon, you stay here.
现在基因组实验室里有电力故障
There's a current flow problem in genomics lab.
你留下去看看怎么回事吧
Why don't you stay and take a look at that.
今天是我生日 大家都走了 为什么我得留下
It's my birthday.Everybody else is leaving, why do I have to stay?
- 因为你与众不同 - 斯迈思 我是说斯迈思先生
- Because you're special, - Smythe, I mean Mr Smythe…
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
生物发电
Bio electrogenesis.
是由有机生物体发电
The generation of electricity by living organisms…
你们好呀
Hey guys.
你们倒是在聚会
At least somebody's partying.
这只是小毛病
You're just a little sick.
我能弄好的
I got your medicine.
即使我为公司设计发明这么多 他们连我的生日都
And on my birthday. After all I've done for this company, designed and created.
警告
Warning.
- 5A区异常 - 我知道 我猜你也不知道今天是我生日吧
- Error in sector 5A - I know, I bet you didn't know it was birthday, huh,
你说呢 卡里
did you, Kari?
你能给我唱生日歌吗
Could you sing "Happy Birthday" For me?
我还是自己唱吧
I'll just have to sing for myself.
吉尔伯特
Gilbert!
- 谁啊 - 我是迈克斯
- What? - It's Max.
你能把32区的总闸拉掉吗
Can you shut down power in sector 32, please?
- 不行 我现在不在公司 - 你说什么
- Forget it I'm out the door. - What do you mean,
我已经上来了 这里很危险
I'm up here, it's dangerous.
- 不好意思 迈克斯 - 喂
- Sorry, Max. - Hello?
我自己去搞定 自己给自己唱生日歌
I'll do it myself and I'll sing to myself.
祝我生日快乐
Happy Birthday…to me.
Happy Birthday…dear Max…
祝我生日
Happy Birthday…
快乐
to me.
系统重装完毕 愿您今天过得愉快
System restored. Have a nice day.
哈利 Oscorp工业之前
Harry, Oscorp's has been under intense public.
因康纳斯博士的事 饱受公众质疑
scrutiny in the wake of Dr. Connors' recent breach of trust.
你是说 公众被惹毛了
You mean, people are pisssed off because.
因为他想把全纽约的人变成巨型蜥蜴
he tried to turn everyone in N.Y city into giant lizards?
正因如此
Given that…
我们叫停了所有有他参与的
all the animal hybrid.
动物杂交项目
program he was involved in were destroyed…
以重塑投资者的信心
to restore investor confidence.
这是奥斯本式的作风
That is the Osborn way.
碍事的人就撇下 是吧
Whoever's inconvenient around here, just get rid of it, right?
现在大家的矛头可能会转向你
Much of that scrutiny may fall on you now.
我们认为合理的推诿是你最好的选择
We felt that plausible deniability was your best option.
没问题 我懂
Sure, sure, I get it.
把价值两千亿的公司留给一个二十岁的小屁孩
Twenty-year-old kid. 200 billion dollar company.
这当爹的是怎么想的
What was dad thinking?
我说你们都是律师 对吧
I mean you're all lawyers…right?
肯定会有人怀疑他是不是老糊涂了
Surely someone must have questioned his sanity in the end.
也肯定有人想过
Someone must have thought.
在法律层面宣布他无判断能力
about having him declared legally incompetent.
这样我们现在这场谈话就简单多了
would have made this conversation a lot easier.
- 哈利 - 叫我奥斯本先生
- Harry… - It's Mr. Osborn.
我们不是朋友
We're not friends.
嗨
Hi.
你是他的助手吧
You were his assistant, right?
你叫什么
What is your name?
- 费利西亚 - 你好 费利西亚
- Felicia. - Felicia.
从今天开始 你们都归费利西亚管
From now on, everybody at this table will work for Felicia.
因为她归我管
because Felicia works for me.
还有谁想说什么吗
Would anybody like to speak up?
很好 这样你们就暂时保住了饭碗
Well good then, you can all keep your job for a little longer.
先生 有位叫彼得·帕克的想见你
Sir… There's a Peter Parker want to see you.
费利西亚 你把这张单子里所有文件找给我
Felicia, I want to see every file on this list.
每一份都要
Every single one.
彼得·帕克 我简直不敢相信是你
Peter Parker. It's like seeing a ghost.
嗨 哈利
Hey, Harry.
好久不见
Random.
- 有十年了吧 - 八年
- What ten years. - It's eight.
也快十年了
Close.
- 找我什么事 - 我看了新闻
- What's up? - It's on the news, man.
听说你父亲去世了 所以我过来想
I heard about your dad and I wanted to come and…
看看你 看看你过得怎么样
see you, check it out, see how you're doing.
我 我刚刚正和一群人
I'm…umm…I'm with some people.
在开会
I'm in the middle of a meeting.
对不起 我不是有意打扰的
I'm sorry, I don't want to intrude,
只是虽然过了很久
I know it has been a long time and.
但我多少理解你现在的处境
I kind of know exactly what you're going through right now.
我父母去世的时候有你在我身边
You were so there for me when my parents…
所以现在我来了
That's why I'm here for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you man.
真的很高兴
Good to see you.
你父亲的事我深表遗憾
Sorry about your dad.
你把牙套摘了
You've got your braces off.
这样你的一字眉就更加瞩目了
and now there's nothing to distract from your unibrow.
这才是你
There it is.
你现在还是每天早上都吹头发吗
Do you still blow drying your hair every morning?
这个嘛 我有一个男仆会帮我举着吹风机
Umm…you know…one of my man servants hold the hair dryer.
但是梳头我自己梳
but I work the comb.
好吧 至少我还是能生活自理的
Okay, so at least I'm not completely helpless.
毕业以后我去了巴西和新加坡
After graduation I went to Brazil and Singapore.
- 这样 - 然后还有欧洲
- That's right. - And then Europe,
- 我去了欧洲 - 我见过你
- you know, I went to Europe. - I saw you.
什么叫你见过我
What do you mean you saw me.
我见过你在杂志上跟一个
I saw you in some magazine with some.
法国超模的照片 你知道是什么吧
French supermodel, you know what I'm talking about?
是啊 哥们
Yeah, yeah, dude,
- 跟模特在一起太伤神了 - 我懂的
- that whole model thing is so exhausting. - I know.
什么情况
What?
你有女朋友吗
You got a lady?
呃 还真是问倒我了
Er…that's the question.
问倒我了
That's the question.
没有吗
Nobody?
没有了
No, I don't.
我也不知道怎么说
I don't know…
我解释不清楚 事情太复杂
I don't know, it's complicated.
我从不把事情复杂化
Yeah, I don't do complicated.
所以她是谁啊 叫什么名字
So what's her name? Who is she?
她叫格温 格温·斯黛西
Her name is Gwen, Gwen Stacy.
- 格温·斯黛西 - 她是你手下的员工
- Gwen Stacy? - She works for you.
真的吗 她是我的员工
Really? She works for me?
她在那里算是半工半读吧
At Oscorp. She does work study at Oscorp.
她是模范员工么
Is she a model employee?
你知道 当年我父亲把我送走以后
You know, when my father sent me away.
我就尝试忘记这里的一切
I tried to forget everything about this place.
这其中也包括你
I guess that kind of includes you.
你不用跟我解释的
You don't have to explain anything to me, man.
我们俩都是被抛弃的人
We both got dumped.
你有试着去搞清你父母离开的原因吗
Did you ever figure out why your parents bailed?
我爸遗物里有个公文包
My dad left a briefcase.
只剩这个了 一公文包的垃圾
Thats all I got, a briefcase full of junk.
无所谓了 我尽量不去想
Whatever, I don't know. I try not to think about it.
这做法管用吗
How's that working out for you?
很管用
Perfectly.
好臂力啊
Dude, nice arm.
手腕而已 关键是手腕技巧
It's just the wrist. It's just all in the wrist, buddy.
- 你好好锻炼也可以的 - 是么
- You could do it too, if you just strengthen up that. - Yeah, right.
但你必须承认
You got to admit though,
这里发生了许多怪事
things have gotten a little crazy around here man.
巨型蜥蜴啊
Giant lizards, and…
蜘蛛小子啊
Spider-Guy.
就一个 一个叫蜘蛛侠的
Just one guy, just one Spider-Man,
或者蜘蛛女侠 我们也不清楚
or woman. We don't know…for sure.
管他呢 他竟然穿着紧身衣爬到树上救猫
Whatever dude. He wears spandex to rescue kittens from trees.
真是大开眼界
So impressed.
我倒是觉得他给了人们希望
I like to think he gives people hope.
什么希望
For what?
也许最终所有事情都会好转的
Maybe eventually everything's gonna be alright.
我希望我能等到那天
I wish I had time for eventually.
这谁啊
Who was it?
麦克斯韦尔·狄龙 电力工程师
Maxwell Dillon, electrical engineer.
无亲无故的
No associates or friends to speak of.
他提交的电网设计被我们化用了
He submitted specs for the grid, that we…appropriated.
那人毫无存在感
The guy was…invisible.
华尔街都在怕哈利那个小屁孩接手
Wall Street is nervous enough of that child, Harry, taking over.
我们得想法把他踢走
We got to find a way to get him out.
这段时间如果媒体
In the meantime if the press.
抓着这场意外不放的话 我们的股市会遭受重创
gets hold of this accident, our stock will crater.
所以就让狄龙先生继续没有存在感吧
So make sure that this Mr. Dillon stays invisible.
这事以后说不定对我们还会有用处
This could prove useful for us in the future.
嗨
Hey.
快走 别挡道
Move over! Get out of the street!
嗨
Hey!
Hi!
你看起来真美
You look amazing.
抱歉 临时把你约出来
I'm sorry for the spontaneous hour, but it was kind of…
没事 我 我不介意的
No, I know. Spontaneous, it's alright. You know?
我觉得现在我们可以
Well, I just figured it was time,
可以重新成为好朋友了
you know…time for us try to be friends.
朋友 好啊 这
Friends, yeah, that's…
很好
great.
我不想让我们的关系太复杂
I just don't want us to be complicated.
我今天才跟别人说过
I just said that to someone.
- 我讨厌复杂 - 简单就好
- I hate complicated. - Keep it simple.
好好好 这样很好 但我想
Okay great, great, yeah, yeah, alright but I mean…
如果我们要成为朋友
if we were to be friends,
我们得约法三章
I think we gotta establish some ground rules.
- 约法三章 - 对啊 约法三章
- Some ground rules? - Yes, some ground rules,
- 比如这个 - 什么
- Like that. - Like what?
看看看 就是这种笑容
Look…look, that laugh, that laugh.
以后不许这么笑了
That's off the table.
我不能这么笑了
My laugh's off the table?
你得笑得更讨人厌点
You gotta figure out a more annoying laugh.
这笑得还是太迷人了
That's still adorable.
才不迷人呢 你要干嘛
That was not adorable. What're you doing…
- 好吧 我也有一条规矩 - 说来听听
- Okay, I've got a ground rule. - Oh, you, what? What's it.
不许用你深邃的大眼睛看着我
Er…don't tell me that I look amazing.
赞扬我很美 行么
with your big brown doe eyes, OK?
我认真说的
I'm really serious about that one.
- 完了 - 怎么了
- Oh no… - What?
- 我又想到了一条 - 什么
- I've just figured out the next ground rule. - What?
别再这样
No more of this.
别再 别再这样揉你的鼻子
No more…no more this nose rub that you do.
- 这样吗 - 别以为我没看到
- This? - Don't think I haven't noticed.
那我要怎么办 现在可是过敏期
What am I supposed to do? It's allergy season.
这简直要了我的命啊 我要
This is killing me, I gotta…
你刚刚质疑我的规则 我不玩了
you just spitting in the face with my ground rules, I'm out.
别这样
Come on!
我先去买冰淇淋 然后我就走了
First we get ice cream, then I'm out.
对 我确实
Umm, yeah, so I did that…
然后我就彻底爱上了
and I got completely addicted.
这个卖韩国肉丸的地方
to this place that has Korean meatballs.
- 你去过吗 - 没有
- Have you been there? - No, no…
那里超棒
It's mind-blowing.
我知道 在第六大道上 你很爱那个地方
That place is at 6th, I know, you love it there.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
你怎么知道我喜欢那里
How do you know I love it there?
因为嘛
Cos' umm…
因为你告诉过我
Cos' you told me.
可是它上个月才开张
It just opened last month.
你一直在跟踪我吗
Have you been following me?
我就知道 多久一次
I knew it. How often?
有时候 一天一次
Just once a day, sometimes.
有时候更频繁
Sometimes more.
为什么
why?
- 你想要保护我吗 - 是啊
- To make sure I'm safe? - Yeah.
这也是我能接近你的唯一方法了
Because that's the closest I can get still being with you.
我要搬去英国了
I'm moving to England.
- 什么 - 真的
- What? - Yeah.
我申请了牛津大学的奖学金
I have a, um…I'm up for a scholarship to Oxford.
分子医学专业的
in molecular medicine.
竞争者有两名
and it's between me and this.
明天我们要进行面试
other kid and there's this oral exam we've to do.
另一个候选人是大一新生 但他只有14岁
and he's like a freshman in college but he's fourteen.
我们俩的机会均等 我希望自己能被选上
and it could be him but might be me, I hope it's me.
选上的话 我就要搬去英国了
And I'm gonna go to…gonna be moving to England.
我还是很期待的
and I'm really excited.
这个 呃
That's…er…
要去英国啊
England?
总部 请求支援
Station, I need a ten-eighty-five.
派一队人去杜菲广场的南角
Send out the units to the southend corner of Duffy Square.
大家请让开 快让开
Everybody get out of the way, please. Get out of the way!
先生 把你的手从电缆上移开 快点
Sir, get your hands away from the cable, right now!
先生 把你的手从电缆上移开
Sir, get your hands away from the cables!
请把手举起来
Let me see your hands, please!
待在原地 不要动
You stay right where you are. Do not move.
不要动 趴在地上
Freeze! Get down, on the ground!
马上趴下
Get down on the ground, now!
- 你们停下 - 马上趴下
- Stop. - Get down on the ground, now!
这不是我的错 别这样
It's not my fault. Stop.
拜托了
Please…
我的天啊
My goodness.
他们看见我了 他们看见我了
They see me…they see me…
他们看见我了 看见我了
- 马上趴下 - 别 别这样做
- On the ground, now! - No…stop. Don't do that.
拜托了
Please.
- 到此为止了 怪胎 - 等等 这不是我的错
- It's over, freak. - Wait, it's not my fault.
这不是我的错
It's not my fault.
我说了 停下来
I said, stop!
真庆幸你不是一位骑警
I'm glad you're not one of those cops that ride a horse.
所有警员注意 停止开枪 等我的命令
All team members…hold your fire and wait for my call.
停止开枪 再重复一遍 停止开枪原地待命
Hold your fire, I repeat, hold your fire and stay down.
- 停下 请停下 - 嘿 亮闪闪的这位
- Stop, stop it! - Yo, Sparkle!
嘿 你好吗
Hey…how are you doing?
- 是你啊 - 是呀 是我 你是哪位
- It's you? - Yeah, I know it's me, who are you?
- 你不记得我了吗 - 我见过你吗
- You don't remember me? - No, should I?
我走在街上的时候差点被车撞到 你抱住了我
I walked into the street, the car almost hit me. You swung me up.
是你救了我 你说你需要我
You saved me. You said you needed me.
是你啊 抱着图纸的那个人
The guy, you're the guy with the blue prints.
对 抱着图纸的
Yes, blue prints.
是的 我记得你
Yes, I remember you,
我当然记得你 你是我的耳目嘛
Of course I remember you, you're my eyes and ears.
- 呃 你叫什么来着 – 你怎么能忘了我
- Er…what's your name again? - How could you forget me?
噢 我记得的 我记得的 别告诉我
Oh, I do, I know it, I know it, don't tell me.
- 我叫迈克斯 - 你是叫迈克斯吗？
- It's Max. - Is it Max?
是的
Yes.
抱歉 我刚才没认出来 你看起来很不一样
I'm sorry, I didn't recognize you with the…you look different.
你怎么样了
How are you?
我不知道怎么回事
I don't know what's going on with me.
我明白的 我相信你
I can see, I…I believe you.
这感觉很陌生 我浑身充满了能量
It's strange…the power that I got so much.
充满了愤怒
I got so much anger.
- 麻烦让一让 - 我明白的
- Excuse me. - I can see that.
我知道你也不想在这儿 看得出你很恐慌
I can see you don't want to be here, I can see you're scared.
因为你不知道自己到底怎么了
cos' you don't know what's happening to you.
我知道你不想伤害任何人
I can see that you don't want to hurt anybody.
- 一切都会好的 - 我已经瞄准了 等待指示
- It's going to be alright. - I got a clear shot, standing by.
我不想要他们再向我开枪
I don't want them shooting me anymore.
他们不会再这么做了
They're not going to shoot you.
嘿 伙计们 这是我的兄弟迈克斯
You guys, this is my buddy Max.
我和你们提起过他 别再朝他开枪了
I told you about Max. No one shoots at Max!
你和我 就只有你和我
You and me, just you and me talking.
哇 喔 待在那儿别动 先别动
Whoa… Stay right there, stay right there.
小心脚下 那可是电网
Just be careful with the grid, it's the electricity.
我只是 我只是希望大家能注意到我
I just…I just wanted everyone to see me.
他如果有所行动 你就开枪
If he makes a move, you take that shot.
就你和我 我们离开这
How about you come with me, go somewhere we can talk,
去别的地方谈谈 好吗
away from all these people…okay?
不 不 别开枪
No, no…stop!
蜘蛛侠 蜘蛛侠
Spidey…Spidey…
你这个愚蠢的怪胎
You stupid freak!
快滚吧 傻子
Fuck off, dummy!
他欺骗了我 开枪射我
He lied to me, he shot me…
闭嘴
Shut up.
你太自私了
You're so selfish.
听我说 迈克斯
Stay with me Max.
- 你陷害我 - 不 我没有陷害你
- You set me up. - No…I didn't set you up.
- 你骗了我 - 不 我是在帮你 让我帮你
- You lied to me. - No, I'm trying to help you, let me help you.
今天是我的生日
It's my birthday.
是时候点蜡烛了
Now it's time for me to light my candles.
你们有看到蜘蛛侠吗
Do we have visual on Spider-Man?
有人看到蜘蛛侠了吗
Does anyone…have visual on Spider-Man?
这样就行了
That's enough.
- 迈克·约翰 - 干得好
- Mike. Big John. - Nice job!
干得好伙计们 很高兴和你们合作
Nice work fellas. It's a pleasure doing business with you.
蜘蛛侠
Spider-Man…
英国吗
England?
真的么
Really?
谈话愉快
Good talk.
关于此次突发事件的报道
Our coverage of this breaking story.
让我们连线现场记者杰西卡·奥布
begins with Jessica Abo at the scene.
好的 站在我身边的是两位目击者
That's right. We're standing here with two eyewitnesses.
他们将告诉我们刚才发生了什么
who are going to tell us what they just saw.
请告诉我们 你们觉得蜘蛛侠是怎么做到的
So tell us. How do you think Spider-Man did it.
他是如何打败刚才那个怪物的
How do you think he beat this creature.
关键在于他的衣服 一定是橡胶材质的
Yeah, it got to be rubberised, Spidey's suit.
这就是为什么他不会触电致死
that's why he didn't get electrocuted.
可能是某种氯丁橡胶 如果是我的话也会用这个
Probably some kind of neoprene. That's what I'll use, honestly…
非常感谢你们接受采访
Thank you very much for the two of you,
目前为止很多问题还尚未有答案
as you can tell so many questions remain unanswered.
但我们会为您带来事件的最新消息
But we will bring you the latest information as it becomes available.
感谢收看杰西卡来自现场的报道
For now, Jessica Abo for New York l…
∮ 当生活令你感到孤立无援 ∮
∮ When life leaves you high and dry ∮
∮ 我会第一时间赶到 只要你有所需要 ∮
∮ I'll be at your door tonight if you need help. If you need help ∮
∮ 哪怕要夺走城市的光亮 ∮
∮ I'll shut down the city lights ∮
∮ 又或是让我欺骗使诈乞讨行贿 只要你安然无恙 ∮
∮ I'll lie, cheat. I'll beg and bribe to make you well, to make you well ∮
∮ 当敌人来袭 我愿带你远离纷扰 ∮
∮ When enemies are at your door, I'll carry you way from more ∮
∮ 只要你有所需要 ∮
∮ If you need help, if you need help ∮
∮ 若你的希望即将破灭 ∮
∮ Your hope dangling by a string ∮
∮ 我将分担你的苦难 只求你安然无恙 ∮
∮ I'll share in your suffering to make you well, to make you well ∮
∮ 请让我相信 你也会这般待我 ∮
∮ Give me reasons to believe that you would do the same for me ∮
∮ 这样我便会毫无保留为你付出 ∮
∮ And I would do it for you for you ∮
∮ 我对你的爱不会减少 ∮
∮ Baby I'm not moving on ∮
∮ 即使你已离开了我 ∮
∮ I love you long after you're gone ∮
∮ 我将为你赴汤蹈火 ∮
∮ For you, for you ∮
∮ 你永远不会孤单而眠 ∮
∮ You will never sleep along ∮
∮ 你的离开不会改变我的爱恋 ∮
∮ I love you long after you gone ∮
∮ 我将为你赴汤蹈火 ∮
∮ For you, for you ∮
∮ 我对你的爱不会减少 ∮
∮ Baby I'm not moving on ∮
∮ 即使你已离开了我 ∮
∮ I love you long after you're gone ∮
∮ 像鼓声般永不停歇 ∮
∮ Like a drum baby don't stop beating ∮
∮ 我的心将像这鼓点永远为你跳动 ∮
∮ Like a drum my heart never stops beating for you ∮
（难道我连你也要失去吗）
∮ 你的离开不会改变我的爱恋 ∮
∮ And long after you're gone gone gone ∮
∮ 无论历经多久 我的爱也不会变
∮ I love you long after you're gone gone gone ∮
网络投票显示 民众对蜘蛛侠的
Online polls show a sudden uptake.
支持率急剧上升
in public sentiment in favour of the web-crawler.
今夜的纽约市似乎欠了他一份恩情
Tonight it would seem New York City owes him a debt of gratitude.
新一代武装装备
Next generation military body armor.
性能包括 更强的机动性 战时伤病治愈
Features include enhanced mobility, battlefield injury repair.
神经系统的实时反馈
Direct nervous system interface.
一般的蜘蛛 与人类的细胞不同
So the common household spider, umm…Unlike human cells,
它们拥有自我治愈的能力
there's a containment power to self-heal.
包括重症感染 组织损伤等等
from severe infection, tissue damage, etc.
所以我们使用放射性同位素与可兼容的人类DNA
and so we used radioactive isotope with compatible human DNA…
欢迎收看贾林斯博士的科教频道
Welcome…to Dr. Jallings science investigator.
今天我们要来谈谈电力
Today we're going to be talking about electricity.
电池 绝缘体 电流
Batteries, insulators, electromagnetic current.
电池可以承受大量输入的电荷
Batteries can withstand a lot of incoming charges.
电池的容量越大
The more powerful the battery,
它所能承受的电荷也就越多
the bigger the charge it can withstand.
但如果输入的电荷超过了放出的电荷
But if the incoming charge exeeds the outgoing charge,
电池就会爆炸 爆炸
the battery might explode! Explode!
在进行此类实验时 请务必做好防护措施
Conducting experiments like this, always wear protective gear.
- 因为你不是无敌的 - 我需要块更大的电池
- You're not invincible. - We're gonna need a bigger battery.
- 谁呀 - 彼得 是我
- Hello? - Pete, it's me.
嘿 哈利 现在几点了
Hey, Harry, what time is it?
很迟了 又或是大清早 不清楚 我一晚上没睡
Late, early, I don't know. I've been up all night.
- 我需要见你一面 - 你还好吗
- I need to see you. - You alright…
其实不太好
Not really, Pete.
我快要死了 但我想你能救我的命
I'm dying…but I think you can help save my life.
你现在看到的是世界首例人类与蜘蛛的杂交体
You're looking at the world's first Human-Spider hybrids.
我们的设想是从它们的腺体中提取毒液
The hope is to extract the venom from their glands.
再将其转化为治愈病变细胞的药剂
and turn that into a cure, an agent that heals diseased cells.
如果我能被治愈
And if I can be cured…
想想这对那些
Imagine what this could do.
阿尔茨海默病患者和癌症患者意味着什么
for other diseases like Alzheimer's even cancer.
他们从未进展到人体试验阶段
They never made it to human trials.
历经14年的研究却一无所获
It's fourteen years of research and nothing to show for it.
除了这个
Except maybe this.
（惊艳！首张蜘蛛侠清晰照片）
- 蜘蛛侠 - 跟他有什么关系
- Spider-Man. - What about him?
他被其中一只蜘蛛咬了 并且成功变异
He was bitten by one of those things then worked.
我不知道这其中的原理 但是
I don't know how and I don't know why…but.
他能做所有蜘蛛能做的事 包括自我治愈
he can do everything else a spider can, including self-heal.
我需要找到他
I need to find him.
我需要他的血
I need his blood.
（搜索）
你需要蜘蛛侠的血
You need Spider-Man's blood?
- 那可以救我的命 - 那可能行不通 哈利
- It will save my life. - It may not, Harry.
也许没那么简单
It may not be that simple.
你知道科特·康纳斯发生了什么 对吧
You saw what happened to Curt Connors, right?
那是他太弱了
Connors was weak.
而我不同 彼得
This is me, Peter.
我不觉得你开着辆采血车
I don't think you can just set up a van.
他就会来献血了
and have him donate it.
我的意思是 当然了
I mean, I'm sure he's.
如果有人到处举着针头 他会敏锐地察觉到
sensitive about people shoving needles…and.
敏锐地察觉么
Probably sensitive?
好吧
Okay, well then,
或许你可以直接敏锐地告诉我他在哪
Maybe you can just sensitively tell me where he is.
- 我自己去求他 - 你说什么
- and I will just go ask him myself. - What?
- 你照到了他 - 所以呢
- You took his picture. - So?
你认识他
You know him.
哈利 我那是从很远的地方照的
Harry, I took a picture from a long way,
我用了长镜头 我并不认识他
I use a long lens, I don't know him.
我重新想了想你在河边说的话
I put together what you said at the river.
我说了什么
What did I…
你说蜘蛛侠给了人们希望
about how he gives people hope.
拜托了
Come on.
（中央服务器被访问 搜索中）
（限制该员工的所有访问 追踪目标位置）
（查无此人）
（无法搜索 请联系管理员）
求你答应吧
Just say yes.
别背对着我
Don't turn your back on me.
我不想和我爸一个下场 彼得
I don't want to end up like my father, Peter.
拜托了
Please.
彼得 求你了 我不想那样死去
Peter, please. I can't.
我会试着找到蜘蛛侠的
I'm going to try and find Spider-Man.
- 嘿 保安怎么会来这里 - 太诡异了
- Hey, what's the security doing here? - That's so weird.
嘿 斯泰西小姐
Hey, Miss Stacy.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
- 你在这干嘛呢 - 你又在这干嘛呢
- What are you doing here? - What are you doing here?
她不在这 去别的楼层看看
She's not here. Check another floor.
你惹上麻烦了
You are in trouble?
- 对 - 那人是谁
- Yeah. - Who's that guy?
基因实验室里发生了一场事故
There was an accident in the genomic lab.
而他们想要掩盖真相
And they're covering it up.
还有昨晚在时代广场的那个人
and I found out that guy from Times Square last night,
我见过他 他是这里的一名电力工程师
I met him. He was an electrical engineer in the building.
对了 他可喜欢蜘蛛侠了 狂热粉丝级别的
and he loved Spider-Man, by the way, he was like a fanatic.
反正我是没感受到他的爱意
I didn't get a love vibe last night,
我只感受到了他想要电死我的信念
I got more of a wanting him to kill me with his electricity vibe.
这正是表达爱意的一种方式嘛
That's actually kind of what it's like to love you.
我在电脑上搜索他
I was searching for him in the computer.
但所有相关资料都被清除了
and all the files were erased.
- 彻底清楚了 - 这公司的典型做法
- It's completely erased. - That's Oscorp.
你呢 你怎么会在这
What about you, why are you here?
- 因为哈利来的
- Harry.
- 奥斯本吗 - 他快要死了
- Osborn? - He's dying.
- 什么意思 - 他快要死了
- What do you mean? - He's dying.
他觉得唯一能救他的是 我的血
And he thinks the only thing going that's gonna his life is my blood,
蜘蛛侠的血
Spider Man's blood.
但是据我所知 如果我给了他 只会害了他
As far as I know, if I give it to him, it could kill him.
甚至更糟
Or something worse.
这里是保洁储物间 格温
This is the maintenance closet, Gwen.
真是老掉牙的藏身处啊
This is the most cliche hiding place you could have chosen.
- 抱歉 - 躲在这里真是蠢爆了
- I'm…sorry. - This is the stupidest hiding place.
真是抱歉没把您带去高端的藏身处啊
I didn't take us to the Bahamas of hiding place.
我不想和你聊英国的事情 因为
I don't want to talk to you about England is because…I don't…
- 你刚刚吻了我 - 对不起 情不自禁就
- You just kissed me. - I know, I'm sorry, I couldn't help it.
感觉怎么样
How do you like it?
- 有点匆忙 - 我知道
- It felt a little rushed. - I know, I know.
计划是这样的 你去乘电梯
This is the plan. You get to the elevator,
- 我来想办法引开他们 - 好的
- I'm going to distract them, okay? - Okay.
抱歉 我竟然把一杯热拿铁洒了你全身
I'm sorry. I just spilled a hot latte all over you.
我什么也没做 哎呀 不是我干的
I didn't do that! Oh, and you too!
你别跑 别跑
Stay right there! Stay right there!
等一等 等一等嘛
Wait, wait, wait, wait! Wait!
停下
Stop.
抱歉咯 我今天笨手笨脚的
I'm sorry…I'm all thumbs today.
- 格温·斯黛西 - 天哪
- Gwen Stacy. - Oh my God!
- 抱歉 - 不好意思
- I'm sorry. - I'm sorry.
没关系
That's ok.
- 你好 我是哈利 - 嗯
- I'm Harry. - Yeah.
- 我是彼得的老朋友了 - 嗯 我知道你是谁 不好意思
- I'm an old friend of Peter's. - Yea, I know who you are. Sorry.
刚刚有点冒失
I was kind of rushing.
不 很抱歉他没介绍我们认识
No, I'm sorry he never introduced us.
我以为你们已经分手了
I thought you two had broken up.
是的 分手了 这事
Yes, we had, it's…
有点复杂
Complicated.
- 复杂 - 彼得就是这样
- Complicated. - He's Peter.
和他有关的事情都不简单
Everything is always complicated with Peter.
- 对啊 - 但这正是他需要你的原因
- Yeah, yeah, it's…you're right. - But that's why he needs you.
不是吗
Right?
帮助他选择该走的路
To help him make his choices clear.
- 很高兴认识你 哈利 - 幸会 格温
- Nice to meet you, Harry. - Yeah, it' such a pleasure, Gwen.
（收治精神病犯人）
你经历了一场可怕的事故
You have been in a terrible accident.
我是卡夫卡医生 我是来帮助你的
I'm Dr. Kafka. I'm here to help you.
当然是了 医生
Of course you are, Doc.
所以你才准备了军用生物刺激电极
That's why you prepared a military grade, biostimulate electrode.
和高强度电容器
High intensity capacitors.
Oscorp工业制造的
The kind they make at Oscorp.
准备这些都是为了帮助我
All of this because you're trying to help me.
你说对了
You are correct.
我是来研究你的
I'm here to study you,
来查明你是什么东西 又为何存在
to understand what you are, why you're.
我会得到我要的结果的
And I will get results.
一向如此
I always do.
你没忘记这所监狱的动力
You do realize you locked me in a prison…
是电吧
that runs on electricity.
我能从墙里和我的血管里感受到
I can feel it in the walls, I can feel it in my veins.
医生 无论你怎么做 都是无法控制它们的
No matter what you do, Doc, you can't contain it.
这就是大自然的力量 而我也是
It's a force of nature, like me.
- 你想知道我有多强大吗 - 当然
- You want to know how powerful I am? - Yeah.
我也想啊
Well, so do I.
好 很好
Good…good.
我很想知道 医生
I'm dying to know, Doc.
那你最好确保这次能杀死我
But you'd better make damn sure that you kill me this time.
因为如果你做不到
Because if you don't…
我会吞噬一切光亮
I'm gonnna kill the light.
城市里的所有人
So everyone in this city,
都将感受到我暗无天日的生活
is gonna know how to feel, to live in my world.
一个没有电也没有善意的世界
A world without power. A world without mercy.
一个没有蜘蛛侠的世界
A world without Spider-Man.
所有人将目睹我的真实面目
And everyone will be able to see me for who I truly am.
你是谁
And who are you?
你不知道吗 我是电光人
Don't you know? I am Electro.
警告 已达到电力承载最高值
Warning. Electrical restrain capacity reaches escape.
立即启动禁闭程序
Initiate lockdown procedure, immmediately.
不错啊 电光人
Very impressive, Electro.
禁闭程序 启动
Lockdown initiating.
梅伯母
Aunt May?
- 你在做什么 - 这些是什么时候做的
- What are you doing? - When did you do this?
你是不是有事瞒着我了 梅伯母
There's something your not telling me, Aunt May.
每次我提到我父母 你都不敢看我
Every time I mention my parents, your eyes go down.
我知道你有事瞒着我 在对我撒谎
I know you're not telling me something. You're lying to me.
- 我知道你很爱我 - 我没有 - 我也很爱你 但你撒谎了
- I know you love me… - I don't. - I know you love me… But you do.
告诉我 那毕竟是我爸爸
You have to tell me. It's my father.
没错 他是你爸爸
Yes, he was your father…
但那并没能阻止他的离去
but that didn't seem to stop him from leaving you.
我需要知道事情的真相
I need the truth.
事实就是 你父母把你留了在我家门前
The truth is that your parents left you here, on our door-step.
年幼的你 生活就此被颠覆
This little boy whose world was turned upside down with no explanation.
我们尽了最大努力照顾你
We did the best, we could.
你的本伯父和我
You Uncle Ben, he and I.
还有谁会来这样照顾你 保护你
Who else was going to care for you and protect you?
担心你呢
And worry about you.
你爸爸吗 他做不到
Your father? No.
是我替你擦鼻子
I was the one who wiped your nose,
逼着你刷牙
who made you brush your teeth…
叫你做作业 洗你的脏内衣
and do your homework. And washed your dirty underwear.
是我 这个没文化没知识的伯母
Me! You stupid, nonscientific aunt,
一个不知该如何养家
who doesn't know how to make ends meet…
只能和年轻人一起上护士学校
who has to take nursing classes, with 22 year old kids,
才能供你上学的伯母
so I can pay for you to go to college.
没有本的日子 我真的不知该怎么做
And I don't know how to do this without Ben. I don't know how.
而此刻 你却满脑子想着那完美的爸爸
And you're dreaming about your perfect father…
那个从未出现过的爸爸 不
Who was never here. No!
我不会告诉你的 你是我的孩子
No, I won't tell you. You're my boy.
对我而言 你就是我的孩子 我不想伤害你
As far as I'm concerned, you're my boy. And I won't hurt you.
我是你的孩子 你是我的一切
I'm your boy. You're my everything.
你做得很好 足够好了
You're enough. You're more than enough.
别误会 但我还是想知道真相
That's not what this is about.Don't get that twisted.
- 我很爱你 - 我知道
- I love you so much. - I know.
没事的
It's okay.
梅伯母
Aunt May…
我需要知道真相
I need to know.
好吧
Alright.
我把我知道的都告诉你
I'll tell you everything I know.
- 但你也许会难以接受 - 没事的
- But It will hurt you. - Okay.
葬礼后的几天
A few days after the funeral…
两个政府工作人员来找我们
Two government men came to see us.
他们说 你爸爸和诺曼·奥斯本
They said the genetic research…
一起进行的那个基因研究 具有巨大的价值
that your father was doing with Norman Osborn was very valuable.
有人愿意花重金购买
And that people would pay a lot for it.
所以他带着研究结果跑了
And that's why he ran off with it.
他们说他是个叛徒 我不敢相信 彼得
They said he was a traitor. I couldn't believe it, Peter.
他们说他背叛了自己的好友 所有人
They told us he betrayed his best friend, all of us,
为了金钱
for the money.
我不明白 这说不通
I don't get it…It doesn't make any sense.
我懂 我也不敢相信
Yes, I know. I didn't believe it.
- 这完全说不通 - 彼得 我也不知道
- This doesn't make any sense… - Peter… I don't know.
这么多年了 我在脑海中想了一遍又一遍
For so long. I would play it over and over in my head.
我到底错过了什么 到底哪里不对了
What had I missed. What had I missed.
他只是个平凡又低调的人
He was just a normal unasuming guy.
同一件破实验室制服穿了20年
He wore the same ratty lab coat for 20 years…
每天早上7点 乘着D线地铁去上班
He took the D train to work, at seven every morning…
晚上6点准时回家
came home at 6 every night.
我不知道
I don't know.
或许每个人都有不为人知的一面
Maybe everyone has a part of themselves they hide…
即使是对于他们爱的人
Even from the people they love.
彼得
Peter.
奥斯本先生
Mr. Osborn.
抬头 是你在找我吧
Look up. Think you were looking for me.
真不敢相信我所看到的
I can not believe my eyes.
蜘蛛侠
Spider-Man.
正是我想找的人
Just the man I wanted to see.
- 你和彼得聊过了吗 - 是的
- You… talked to Peter? - Yep.
我很想帮你 奥斯本先生 我真的很想
I want to help you, Mr. Osborn. I really, really do.
但是我不能把血给你 至少现在不能
I can't give you my blood. Not right now.
- 什么 - 那样太危险了
- Excuse me? - It's too dangerous.
如果我们的血不相容 你会死
If our blood is not compatible, you could die.
我已经离死不远了
I'm already dying.
- 你的血不会让我多死一次 - 但可能使你恶化
- Your blood can't make me die more. - But it could do something worse.
行吧
Okay.
你要多少
Alright. How much?
- 多少什么 - 多少钱
- How much what? - How much do you want?
一艘船还是一架飞机 还是钱 你要多少
A boat? You want a plane? You want money? How much do you want?
- 我不想要你的钱 - 得了吧 每个人都想要我的钱
- I don't want your money. - Everybody wants my money.
我不想
I don't.
你不是大家的救星吗
I thought you save people.
你一直在做的不就是拯救他人的性命么
I thought that's what you do, is you save people's lives.
而你却要眼睁睁地看着我死去
You just gonna let me die.
我现在是在保护你
I'm trying to protect you right now.
你只是在保护你自己罢了
You're trying to protect yourself.
我们只是需要一点时间
Look…We just need a bit more time…
我没有时间了 你走吧
I do not have time. Get out.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是个骗子 蜘蛛侠
You're a fraud, Spider Man.
- 能和你说句话吗 - 我在赶时间
- Can I to talk to you for a second. - I'm running late right now.
就一会会
It's only gonna take a second.
给我点时间 就一件事 说完我就走
Give me some time. One thing. Then I'm gone.
事情乱套了
Everything's a mess.
我父母 我所了解的一切都是谎言
My dad my mum, everything I thought about them, lies.
谎言 谎言 谎言 什么都说不通
Lies, lies, lies. Nothings make sense any more.
噢 还有哈利的问题
So here we are. I gotta figure out things with Harry.
我当然想救他
Because, of course I want to save him. You know.
我想救他 因为他是我最好的哥们
I want to sve him, because he's my best pal.
我的血可能奏效 也可能失效
And what if my blood works? But what if it doesn't?
我不知道 什么都不知道
I don't know. I got no idea.
我的天哪
Oh…god.
脑子一片空白
I got nothing.
格温 我现在唯一能想到的只有
The only thing I keep coming back to… Gwen is…
斯泰西小姐 我带你上楼吧
Miss Stacy, shall I take you upstairs?
好的 不好意思
Yes, I'm so sorry.
对不起 我已经迟到了 能再等我一下吗
I'm so sorry…I'm already late… Can I have just one moment?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 这里是哪里 - 牛津大学的最后一轮面试
- Where are we? - This is my last interview for Oxford.
牛津 我不知道
Oxford… I don't know.
不好意思打扰你 尊贵的女士
I'm sorry to bother you, my fair lady, madam.
我是谁 我是约翰·霍普金斯
But who am I? I am John Hopkins.
来自哈佛的年轻教授
I'm one of the young professors at Harvard,
我正想让她来加入
and I'm trying to get her to be in my…
我的团队
part of my team, for a while now.
她是我认识的最佳人选 一位科学天才
And she is the best person I know, and a scientific genius.
总而言之 天佑女王
Anyway, "God save the Queen, "
- 刚才发生的一切 我表示抱歉 - 彼得
- I'm sorry that everything's happening right… - Peter!!!
你能再等我一会吗
Can you just wait for one second?
彼得
Peter!
彼得 你刚刚想说什么
Peter. What do you want to say to me?
你唯一能想到的事情
What's the one thing?
我必须得去英国 彼得
I have to go to England, Peter.
这对我来说很重要
It's important to me.
或许我们的人生轨迹不同吧
Maybe we are just on different paths right now.
我不知道
You know, I don't know.
我们的轨迹不同
We were just going different ways.
我得走了 我真的得走了
I gotta go. I gotta go.
格温
Gwen.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你好 刚才抱歉了
Hi.Sorry.
每天早上7点 乘着D线地铁去上班
He took the D train to work, every morning at seven,
晚上6点准时回家
came home at 6 every evening.
（罗斯福 地铁 D列车）
（运输研究：废弃车站）
罗斯福秘密站台 61号铁路
Roosevelt Secret station, Track 61.
建在珀欣广场下面 纽约市D线的隐蔽分支段
A secret subterranean extension of New York's D line under Pershing Square.
在这里罗斯福总统能被秘密转移
Originally built to tranport President Franklin Roosevelt away from the public eye,
对众人隐瞒他小儿麻痹的病情
to keep his polio secret for the American people.
奥斯本先生
Mr Osborn.
你没事吧 有什么我能帮到你的
You alright? Is there anything I can get you?
除非你能让那些蜘蛛起死回生 否则没有
No, unless you can bring those spiders back to life.
- 蜘蛛 - 那些被他们销毁的
- Spiders? - The ones that they destroyed.
「为了重塑投资者的信心」
"To restore investors confidence."
回家吧 费利西亚 放一天假
Go home, Felicia. Take the day off.
哈利
Harry!
我想还有别的办法
I think there may be another way,
得到你想要的
to get what you're looking for…
我听到门肯和其中一个安保负责人说话
I overheard Menken talking with one of our security's head.
他们在毁掉那批蜘蛛前提取出了毒液
Before they destroyed the spiders, they had the venom extracted.
你说什么
What are you saying?
那样他们既不会惹官司
That way they could comply with the.
也可以留着数据以备不时之需
lawsuits but still keep the data whenever it became useful.
- 它在哪 - 这栋楼里
- Where is it? - Somewhere in the building.
一个写着「特殊项目」的地方
Somewhere off the books called "Special Projects".
特殊项目 上一次进入 一小时前
Special Projects. Last received entry: 1 hour ago.
由哈利·奥斯本批准
Approved by Harry Osborn…
进入档案Ravenscroft
Accessing Ravenscroft archive.
713号文件
File seven-one-three.
什么玩意
What the hell?
71号文件 对象 迈克斯·狄龙
File seven-one. Subject: Dillon, Max.
然后我会吞噬一切光亮
…and then I'm going to kill the light,
这座城市的所有人
so everyone in this city.
就会知道活在我的世界里是什么感觉
will discover how it feels to live in my world.
一个没有电的世界 一个没有蜘蛛侠的世界
A world without power. A world without Spider-Man.
警告 你的访问权限被撤销
Warning. Your user access has been revoked.
他很忙 你们不能进去 他很忙
He's busy. You can't go in there. He's busy.
- 你在干什么 - 更切题的问题是你在干什么
- What did you do? - A more relevant question is what did you do?
一个员工死了
An employee is killed and.
你作为CEO却把事情掩盖了
your first action as CEO, you covered it up!
不 是你掩盖了
No, you covered it up and then.
然后以我的名义把他关在那个鬼地方
you buried him in the bug house using my name.
Ravenscroft是一个
Ravenscroft is a timeworn.
用来研究提高心理素质的老机构
Institution devoted to mental improvement.
你在那里用人做实验
You're experimenting on people in there.
进步得有人奠基
Progress has its stepping stones.
现在 考虑到你的
Now, in light of your.
欺诈性犯罪行为 你已经被
deceptive criminal actions, you have been…
我要怎么表述的委婉一点 开除了
how do I put this gently… fired.
你别想把我也埋起来
You're not going to bury me too.
对我来说你已经半身在地下了
Looks to me like you're halfway in the ground already.
这只是时间问题 你会死得很难看
It's only a matter of time. You're going to die a horrible death,
就像你的父亲
like your father.
区别是 没人会怀念你
The difference is, no one is going to miss you.
- 把他赶出去 - 等等
- Get him out. - Wait, wait!
我自己会走
I know my way out.
（罗斯福站）
我的名字是理查德·帕克
My name is Richard Parker.
不管外界怎么形容我
Whatever lies will be told about me,
我都想要这个世界知道真相
I would like the world to know the truth.
Oscorp已经是基因研究的先锋
Oscorp was already a leader in genetic research.
在诺曼·奥斯本
when Norman Osborn made.
和国外军事组织达成交易
a deal with a foreign military organization.
来继续资助我研究的时候
to continue funding my research.
然后我发现了他们要拿我的研究去做什么
And I discovered what they were going to use it for.
武器 当然是生化武器 所以我拒绝了
Weapons, biological weapons of course. So I refused.
于是他们把我排除在计划外
And now to eliminate me from the picture,
诺曼·奥斯本针对我伪造了证据
Norman Osborn has falsified evidence against me.
来夺取我的研究成果
in order to take control of my work.
需要帮助吗
Can I help you?
你可以把门打开 我是哈利·奥斯本
Yea, you can open the gate. I'm Harry Osborn.
我想要见一个在隔离区的病人
There's a patient in that isolation unit I need to see.
乔 这是来自Oscorp的奥斯本先生
Joe, this is Mr. Osborn from Oscorp.
抱歉先生 没有黄色挂牌
Sorry sir, without a yellow badge,
你不能通过这里
you can't even pass this point.
不过 没有关系
Well, it doesn't matter because.
因为还有一些东西是诺曼不知道的
there is something else that Norman doesn't know.
我注入蜘蛛体内的人体DNA
The human DNA that I implanted in the spiders.
是我自己的
was my own.
也就是说没有我 没有我的血脉
Which means that without me, without my bloodline,
Oscorp永远不能复制或者继续我的实验
Oscorp can never replicate or continue my experiments.
继续给电光人注射
Keep Electro incubated,
400毫克硫喷妥钠
with four hundred milligrams of sodium iopental…
我已经 我已经把能毁掉的档案都毁掉了
I've…I've destroyed as much as possible from the archives.
但我没有足够时间杀死所有蜘蛛
but I didn't have time to kill all the spiders.
作为一个科学家 我只有一个选择
So as a scientist, my choice is very clear now.
我必须消失 我要离这里越远越好
I have to disappear. I have to get as far away from here as I can.
但作为一个父亲
but as a father.
这意味着 我不能再见到我的儿子了
it means, I may not see my boy again.
而没有什么比我的儿子彼得更重要
and nothing is as important to me as my son, Peter.
这世上都没有
Nothing in this world.
但我有责任
But I have a responsibility.
从我所创造出的东西手里保护这个世界
to protect the world from what I've created.
保护我的儿子远离奥斯本可以引起的祸乱
and protect him from what I know Osborn is capable of.
人们会因为我的所作所为
People will say I'm a monster.
说我是一个怪物
for what I've done.
也许他们是对的
Maybe they're right.
我总以为我还有很多时间
I always thought that I'd have more time.
- 爸爸 爸爸 - 不好意思
- Dad…Dad!… - I'm sorry.
镇静剂 关闭
Sedation…off…
我会放你出去 不过我们没多少时间了
I'm gonna get you out of here, alright? But we don't have much time.
- 你是谁 - 我是哈利·奥斯本 我想和你做笔交易
- Who are you? - I'm Harry Osborn. I want to make you a deal.
- 我应该杀了你 - 拜托
- I should kill you. - Come on.
想得长远一点 迈克斯 我不是你要的仇人
Think big, Max. I'm not the one you want.
你想找的是蜘蛛侠 而我可以帮你
You want Spider-Man and I can give him to you.
但我要先提个要求
But…I need something first.
我要你带我进Oscorp
I need you to get me to Oscorp.
带你进去 那是你的地盘
Get you in? You own it.
不再是了 我们都被撵出来了
Not anymore. Oscorp betrayed us both.
所以没有你我进不去
So I can't get in there without you.
没有我你也离不开这里
and you you can't get out of here without me.
- 怎么回事 - 有人在隔离层触发警报
- What's happening?? - Someone pulled an alarm in the iso unit…
立刻叫一个拦截小队过去
Get a containment team in there now!
你不可能知道我要什么
You can't possibly know what I want.
你提交了输电网的设计
You submitted the design for the.
他们偷了你的设计现在你想要回来
grid and they stole it and now you want it back.
你就是想把属于你的东西要回来
You just wanna take back what's yours!
- 怎么要回来 - 这座城市所有的电力
- How? - All the power is in the city,
迈克斯 就在你指尖
Max, and its right at your fingertips.
只要你切掉所有电
Once you shut down the grid…
蜘蛛侠就会来找你 我要你让他流血
Spider-Man will come to you and I want you to make him bleed!
撞开它 撞开它
Break it! Break it!
迈克斯 我们没时间了
Max, we don't have much time.
走 走 走
Go… go… go.
给我一个相信你的理由
Give me one reason why.
- 我凭什么相信你 - 因为我需要你
- I should trust you? - Because I need you!
- 你需要我 - 对 我需要你
- You need me? - Yes, I need you.
你是我活下去唯一的机会
You are my only chance that I have at surviving.
- 你需要我 - 我需要你
- You need me? - Yes, I need you.
我需要你 求你了 求你了
I need you…please, please!
我知道被抛弃的感觉 求你了 迈克斯
I know what its like to be thrown away…Please…Max!
我需要你 我需要你
I need you! I need you!
你想做我的朋友
You want to be my friend?
我以为我们已经是朋友了
I thought we were already friends?
我有过一个朋友
I had a friend once.
结果不太好
It didn't work out.
我也是
Yea, me too.
让我们去抓那头蜘蛛吧
Then let's go catch a spider.
你收到一条新语音
You have one new voice message.
嗨 彼得 是我
Hi, Peter, it's me.
我 我被牛津大学录取了
I…I got into Oxford. Woo-hoo.
真的很激动
It's very exciting.
我刚刚路过你家
I came by your house a little bit ago and.
你不在 所以
I…You weren't there and so.
我现在在去机场的路上
I'm on my way to the airport right now.
因为我发现有一个暑假班
because there's this summer class I found out about.
我觉得这样也许会
and I thought that it would somehow.
轻松一点 我想
be easier, I guess, this way.
也许是时候放下了
I think that maybe it's time to let this go…
这并不是因为我不爱你了
and that's not because I don't love you,
正是因为我爱你
it's actually because I do.
所以 嗯 再见
So, umm…goodbye.
- 我们得走了 - 为什么 怎么回事
- We have to move now! - Why? What's happening?
记得我吗
Remember me?
天哪 天哪 看看这些桌子
Oh my oh my, how the tables have turned.
我知道你很惊讶
I know it's hard to admit but.
不过这一切多么酷炫啊
how spectacular a move is this?
- 我说的没错吧 - 没错
- Am I right? - Right, that's right.
行 那么 仙女教母
OK, so, Fairy Godmother,
是时候让我许个愿了
it's time to grant me a wish.
- 我要进入特殊 - 你怎么敢回来
- I want into special… - How dare you come back in here?
你这个目中无人 一无是处 乳臭未干的混小子
You recalcitrant, unworthy, defective, urchin, freak!
噢 我真抱歉
Oh…God I'm sorry,
这不是我们想听到的答案
that's just not the answer we were looking for.
准备电击
"Clear."
欢迎回到附加题
Welome back to the bonus round.
散个步吧 如何
Let's take a walk, shall we?
电网全是你的了
The grid is all yours.
蜘蛛毒液 把它给我
The spider venom, give it to me.
- 这些都是什么 - 未来
- What is all these stuff? - The future.
拿一个出来
Load one up.
不会有用的 我们都测试过了
It won't work. We ran every diagnostic test.
除了人体试验
Apart from human trials…
你们已经在人体上试过了
You've actually already run human trials.
只不过你太蠢了不知道
you're just too stupid to know it.
注射 快
Do it. Now.
解药一直在你的手上
You had it all this time!
（检测到严重伤害）
（治愈程序启动）
是蜘蛛侠
It's Spider-Man!
- 停车 - 小姐 我根本没动过
- Stop the cab. - Lady, I aint even moving!
- 你有没有收到我的消息 - 什么消息
- Did you get my message? - What's the message?
- 挂在那的消息 - 噢那个 是你啊
- The message over there. - Oh that! It was you?
- 别装了 - 我都没想到
- Don't do that. - I couldn't make it up.
我来告诉你是什么 上面说「我爱你」
I tell you what it says, it says "I love you"
因为我爱你
because I love you.
无意冒犯 不过你错了
No offense but you're wrong.
- 错哪了 - 你说我们
- What would that be? - You're wrong about us.
在不同的轨迹上 并不是 你就是我今后要走的路
being on different path. We're not on different path, you're my path!
我知道我无法时刻做到最好
I know I'm not always going to be my best.
我知道这世上有太多
and I know there's so many.
我们不该在一起的理由 我知道
reasons why we shouldn't be together, I know that.
但 我已经受够了
Well, I'm tired of them all.
我不想听到其中任何一个
I'm tired of every sinlge one of it.
如果我要做个选择
If I'm gonna to make a choice,
那我选你
then I choose you.
所以
So…
我想的是
here's my thought.
英国
England.
我们一起去
Both of us.
我要跟着你 你去哪我都跟着你
I'm following you now. I'm just going to follow you everywhere.
我这辈子跟定你了
I'm just going to follow you the rest of my life.
我是说 在英国 也有人犯罪
I mean…they got crime there…in England.
好像 有一堆罪犯
They got tons of crime, it seems.
- 一大堆 - 对 他们有 开膛手杰克
- Tons… - Yea, they got…Jack the Ripper.
人们还没抓到他 你相信吗
They haven't caught Jack the Ripper yet, can you believe that?
那是什么
What the hell is that?
是不是迈克斯
Is that Max?
他一定把整个城市的电都切断了
He must have cut the power to the whole city.
- 全黑了 - 嘿 我要技术人员现在过来
- Totally black! - Hey, I need tech-ops up here right now!
电话坏了 找个人下去叫技术人员
Phones are down. Somebody go down and grab tech-ops…
嘿 把你们记得的都写下来
Hey… write down what you remember, people.
应该有什么应急方案 对吧
There's gotta be some kind of a "Blackout plan", right?
用来备用
Some kind of backup.
发电厂旁边有个重启装置
There's an emergency reset at the power plant.
如果他控制了输电线
If he got the transmission lines,
就再也不能使用重启了
they never gonna get this back up.
我要怎么阻止他
How am I going to stop him?
每次我靠近他 他就烧坏我的蛛网发射器
Every time I get close to him, he fries my web-shooter.
那你有没有试过接地
Okay, have you tried grounding them?
试过 我什么都试过了 橡胶 塑料
Yes, I tried everything, rubber, plastic…
- 你试过磁化他吗 - 我没 磁化过他
- Did you try magnetizing him? - I didn't…try magnetizing him.
好的 还记得八年级的科学课么？
Okay, well, remember eighth grade Science class?
如果你用电池磁化钉子
If you magnetize a nail with a battery…
- 就会产生电荷 - 对
- You cause an electric charge. - Yes…
纽约塔台 这里是泛美航空273航班
New York approach…this is Pan National 273 on approach…
能收到么
How do you hear?
- 塔台 能收到吗 - 无线电正常 不是我们的问题
- Approach, do you copy? - Radio is working, it's not us.
各位不要惊慌 所有人回到车上去
Do not panic, everyone, please return to vehicle!
回到车上去 保持冷静
Go back to your car, remain calm!
不要惊慌 所有人回到车上去 各回各家
Do not panic! Everyone return to your vehicle! Go to your home!
- 警官 - 蜘蛛侠
- Officer! - Spider-Man!
我爸爸乔治·斯黛西曾是这个辖区的警长
My father was Captain George Stacy at your precinct,
我知道他 你能帮你什么吗
Yeah, I know who he was. What can we do for you?
我需要跨接电缆
Jumper cables!
- 跨接电缆 - 对 还有铜丝
- Jumper cables? - Yes and…copper wire.
- 我说话声音是不是比平时大 - 是
- Am I talking louder than I usually talk right now? - Yes.
- 你没问题的 - 好的 开始吧
- You're still doing fine. - Alright, do it!
好的 再试试 快点 快点
Okay, do it. Try…try…Hurry…hurry…
- 好了 有用了 - 这就是
- Okay, it works, good. - And that,
- 为什么你只是第二名 - 又秀优越了啊
- is why you were number two in Midtown. - Rubbing it in? Okay.
- 我要走了 - 我跟你一起去
- I gotta go. - I'm coming with you.
格温 你不能跟着我
Gwen, you're not coming with me.
- 不 我要去 - 不行 这太危险了
- Yes I am. - Come on…it's too dangerous.
我要去 我看过电网设计图 还知道怎么重启系统
I'm coming with you. I've seen the grid specs and I know how to reset the entire system.
我一定要去 你知道你需要我的
I'm coming with you. You know that you need me.
那好吧 把这个关上
Then come with me. Shut that thing.
对不起 我爱你 不要恨我
Sorry, I love you. Don't hate me.
彼得
Peter!
我们得解决这个事
We gotta work with this.
他们还没把发电机带回来 叫工程师来
They're still not back with the generator. Get me engineering!
我需要一个人工呼吸器 马上
I need a respirator right now!
我来准备电池
I'll get the battery operated.
稍等
Hang on.
现在看见我了么 蜘蛛侠
Can you see me now, Spider-Man?
是时候直面我们的命运了
It's time to meet our destiny.
塔台 我们遇到了一些电子干扰
Tower, we're experiencing some kind of electrical disturbance.
仪表一塌糊涂 雷达没有反应
Instruments are going haywire, radar is down.
我们在盲飞呢 听得到么
We're flying blind out here, do you copy?
塔台 我们在等待指示 到底发生了什么
Tower, repeat, we're "Standby" only, what is happening?
长官 有两架飞机的航线即将交汇
Sir, there're two inbound flights on intersecting path!
- 还有多长时间相撞 - 四分半钟
- Time to impact? - Four and a half minutes.
计时 快开始计时
Clock it… Clock it right now.
来不及了 蜘蛛侠 是我设计了这个电网
You're too late, Spider-Man. I designed this power grid.
现在我要拿走我应得的了
Now I'm gonna take back what is rightfully mine.
我要一切都臣服于我
I want control of everything.
- 我就是他们的神 - 一位叫「亮闪闪」的神么
- And I will be like a God to them. - A God named "Sparkles?"
这次别想了 你只有这么点本事么 来吧
Not this time. Is that all you got? Come on!
来吧
Come on!
准备好放弃没
You ready to give up?
真感谢你 格温·斯黛西
Oh, thank you, Gwen Stacy.
加把劲 这是你自己的骨头 肌肉 器官啊
Shake it off. This is your bones, muscles and your organs.
哦 天哪
Oh boy!
我讨厌这歌
I hate this song!
蜘蛛侠 我猜你没想到会这样吧
Spider-Man, bet you never saw this coming…
搞什么啊
Really?
你居然把我绑在车上 你是野蛮人么
You wired me to a car, what are you, a caveman?
你不该来这的
You shouldn't be here.
你把我绑在那就去战斗了 我知道怎么帮助你
You tie me up to go off to war? I know how to help you!
你在这儿干嘛
What're you doing here?
我了解这个电网 我可以重启系统
I know the grid best. I can reset the system.
你不该在这儿 我没胡闹
You can't be here right now. I'm not messing around.
你不能留在这里 这太危险了
You can't be here right now. This is insane!
没人能为我做决定 知道么 没人
Nobody makes my decisions for me, alright? Nobody!
这是我的选择 明白么
This is my choice, okay?
我的选择
My choice.
- 快走吧 - 是我来决定
- Go! - This is Mine!
好了 我们怎么阻止他
Now how do we stop him?
好吧 他用电 他就像个电池
Okay, so he uses electric. He's like a battery.
所以当你给电池充电过度会怎么样
So what happens when you overcharge a battery?
- 它会爆炸 - 对
- It explodes. - Right!
所以我们用他自己的力量对付他 非常好
So we use his power against him, perfect!
我想我能重新连上电源线
I think I can reconnect the power line.
但是 我需要你重启系统
but what I need you to do, I need you to reset the system.
我说打开电源时 你就打开
Okay when I say you turn that power on, you turn it on.
- 无论情况如何 - 彼得
- No matter what. - Peter…
无论如何
No matter what.
快去 快去
Go! Go!
距相撞还有六十秒
60 seconds to impact.
现在打开 格温 就是现在
Now, Gwen, do it now…
过载 13980.1伏
Overload 13980.1V.
687号航班
Unit 687.
这里是拉瓜迪亚塔台 向280方向急转
This is La Guardia tower, turn immediately to heading two-eight-zero.
重复一遍 向280方向回避
Incoming traffic, I repeat two-eight-zero.
好了 大家回到岗位上 来帮他们降落
Okay people, back to work, let's land these planes.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
感谢上帝 有电了 大家继续工作
Thank God, alright! Alright, we're back, everyone, let's go.
你还能赶上航班吗
Are you still able to make it to your flight?
格温 站那儿别动
Gwen, stay there.
彼得
Peter.
当你说蜘蛛侠说不的时候
When you said Spider-Man said no,
其实是「你」在说「不」
you meant "You" Said "No"
哈利 你做了什么
Harry, what did you do?
是你逼我的
What you made me do.
我当你是朋友 你却背叛了我
You were my friend and you betrayed me!
不 我只是想保护你
No, I was trying to protect you.
- 你看看我 - 嘿 一切都会没事的
- Look at me! - Hey. It's gonna be okay.
会好起来的
This is gonna be alright.
你根本不给人希望 你剥夺了我的希望
You give people no hope. You take it away.
- 不是这样的 哈利 - 我也要剥夺你的希望
- No, Harry. - I'm going to take away yours!
不 格温 快跑
No, Gwen…run…
哈利 放她下来
Harry, Harry put her down!
哈利 快停下来
Harry, stop this right now.
你不是这样的人 哈利 放她下来
This isn't you, Harry, this is not you. Harry, put her down!
- 哈利 - 哈利已经死了
- Harry! - Harry's dead!
哈利 这是我们俩之间的事 你想打一架么
Harry, this is between you and me. You wanna fight?
来打我吧 放她走
Fight me, let her go!
你还好吧
You okay?
我抓到你了 我要把你放下来一点
I got you, I'm going to put you down right here.
格温
Gwen.
呼吸啊
Breathe!
你还好么
You okay?
别离开我 别离开我 不要离开我
Stay with me, stay with me, stay with me, you stay with me.
格温
Gwen.
Gwen!
格温不要啊 求你了
Gwen…no, please!
求你了
Please!
我不能没有你
I can't do…
让我们单独谈谈
Leave us.
有进展了么
You made progress?
我找到了几个合适的候选人
I laid down and find several worthy candidates.
蜘蛛侠消失了
Now that Spider-Man's gone…
这城市也将大不相同
the city will never be the same.
我可就指着这个呢
Oh…I'm counting on that.
说到进展 你看起来好多了
Speaking of progress, you're looking better.
时好时坏
It comes and goes.
接着说吧
Tell me more.
- 你想要招募多少人 - 尽量精简
- How many men did you have in mind? - I want to keep it small.
你需要的一切都在Oscorp
Everything you need is already at Oscorp.
准许进入 欢迎菲尔斯先生
Access granted. Welcome, Mr. Fiers.
- 第一个志愿者是谁 - 阿列克谢·西斯艾维奇
- Who is our first volunteer? - Aleksei Sytsevich.
无期徒刑犯
Apparently serving a life sentence.
他是最想加入我们的
He is most eager to join us.
很好
Good.
就从他开始
Start with him.
俄籍犯人阿列克谢·西斯艾维奇在不明团伙的帮助下
Russian gangster Aleksei Sytsevich was broken.
从号称铜墙铁壁的监狱中
out of a classified penitentiary known simply as "The Vault"
成功潜逃
by an unknown team of men.
这是继五个月前蜘蛛侠消失后
It's yet another example of increased criminal activity.
犯罪活动增加的另一个迹象
since the disappearance of Spider-Man 5 months months ago.
蜘蛛侠的消失在城市中心留下一个空洞
The webslingers absence has left a hole in the heart of the city.
无论你们相信与否 就连
Believe it or not even the New York City.
纽约警方也和纽约民众一样
Police Department has joined the chorus of New Yorkers.
开始希望蜘蛛侠归来
in hoping for the return of the webslinger.
全世界都在询问同一个问题
The entire world seems to be asking the same question:
蜘蛛侠去哪了
Where is Spider-Man?
没有那蜘蛛侠真不好
Too bad without that spider-guy.
他消失了真糟糕 好像大家真的很需要他
Too bad he disappeared, seems like everybody really needs him.
你去哪
Where you going?
- 不知道 - 彼得
- I'm not sure. - Peter…
你到底要去哪
Where are you going?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道吗 真是有趣
You know what? It's so funny…
我一直想把这儿收拾一下
I've been trying to clean up around here, get organised and.
想把本的东西装箱
been putting some of Ben's stuff…in boxes.
有趣的是箱子越沉 我就越轻松
It's funny that the heavier the box gets, the lighter I feel.
你要把他的东西都扔掉么
You throwing his stuff away?
不 怎么可能
No, no, God no.
我不会那样做 它们是我的一部分
I couldn't do that. It's a part of me.
我只是在
I'm just…finding…
为它们找个更好的地方
a better place for it.
再看它们最后一眼
I'm gonna take one last look…
然后就把它们放回属于它们的地方
and then I'm gonna put it where it belongs.
在今天这样美丽的日子 人们容易感受到希望
It is easy to feel hopeful on a beautiful day like today.
但生活中也总有不如意
But there will be dark days ahead of us too.
当你感到孤独的时候
There will be days when you feel all alone.
更需要心怀希望
and that's when hope is needed most.
不管情况有多糟糕
No matter how bad it gets.
前途有多迷茫 请向我保证
or how lost you feel, you must promise me.
你都会紧握希望
that you will hold on to hope.
让其长存
Keep it alive.
我们必须比苦难更强大
We have to be greater than what we suffer.
我的愿望就是 你们能与希望融为一体
My wish for you is to become hope.
人们需要希望
People need that.
即使我们失败了又何妨
And even if we fail, what better way is there to live.
看看周围吧
As we look around here today,
正是这些朋友造就了现在的我们
that all of the people who help make us who we are,
我知道这像是一番告别
I know it feels like we're saying 'goodbye'
但我们都会把对方
But we'll carry a piece of each other.
变成自己的一部分继续生活下去
into everything that we do next.
时刻提醒自己 我们到底是谁
to remind us of who we are.
如果真到了别离的时刻 我会说
and if we were meant to be,
我与你们度过了美好的四年 我会想念你们的
I've had a great 4 years with you. I'll miss you all very much.
快走 快点
Let's go! Move it!
我现在位于帕克大道56街
I'm here live on Park Avenue 56th Street.
这里一片混乱
where it's complete chaos.
一个在武装战甲中的人
A man in some sort of weaponised armored suit.
正在市中心大搞破坏
is wreaking havoc on midtown.
我是犀牛人 我说过我一定会回来的
I'm Rhino. I told you I would be back.
豪尔赫 不
Jorge, no!
停火 所有人 停火
Hold your fire. Everybody hold your fire.
小孩 你得
Kid, you got to get…
看呐 纽约
Look, New York.
蜘蛛侠回来了
Spider-Man is back.
那是我的孩子
That's my baby.
真勇敢啊孩子
Brave boy, huh.
我吓到你了么 小鬼
Does Aleksei scares you, little boy?
蜘蛛侠 你好
Hey, Spider-Man.
- 我知道你会回来的 - 谢谢你为我站出来
- I knew you'd come back. - Yeah, thanks for stepping up for me.
你是我见过的最勇敢的孩子
You are the bravest kid I've ever seen.
我来处理这家伙
I'm gonna take care of this jerk,
你去照顾你妈妈 好吗
you go take care of your mom…okay?
好了快走吧 走吧
Alright, get out of here, go, go.
你要来打我了吗 现在就来吗
Will you fight me, will you fight me now?
代表纽约所有的好人
On behalf of the fine people of New York city.
和所有真正的犀牛们
and real rhinos everywhere…
把你那机器小爪子举起来
I ask you to turn your mechanised paws in the air!
不 我可以捏碎你 我可以毁掉你
Never! I can crush you! I can destroy you!
你要让我下来
You're gonna have me come down.
- 然后杀掉我吗 - 对
- there so that you can kill me? - Yes!
我马上就来 唉 还是家里好啊
I'll be right there. Ah…there's no place like home.
《超凡蜘蛛侠2》